# Sukhpreet Singh

Software Developer

4377752263 sukhpreets6718@gmail.com github.com/Sukhpreet-s

## **SUMMARY**

I am a motivated junior developer with 2 years of experience in the industry with building softwares including web and desktop applications. I am looking for an opportunity to design and build high quality products at large scale with a team of smart and talented colleagues.

#### SKILLS

**Technical skills:** Java, C#/.NET, JavaScript, PHP | HTML, CSS, React, Vue, Angular | MySQL, MongoDB | Spring Boot, ASP.NET, Express | AWS S3, Azure web apps | Kafka, Linux, Docker, Git, Networking

**Soft skills:** Effective communication skills, Strong problem-solving skills, Great attention to detail, Team player

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Javascript Developer: KGS Research

December 2021 - Present

- Created JavaScript solutions for the front-end of a survey platform overcoming its limitations..
- Worked closely with the software developer team to improve the functionality of the applications.
- Collaborated with the team to design and build multiple tools to help automate daily tasks.

## Full Stack Developer: Georgian College

May 2020 - December 2021

- Developed full-stack features for innovative web application with various complexities.
- Maintained and Improved existing software to ensure better user experience.
- Everyday tech: Vue/Vuex, Spring Boot services, MongoDB, Kafka, Git, Jira, Confluence.

## **EDUCATION**

Computer Programmer Co-op Diploma (2 years): Georgian College

May 2018 - Dec. 2020

Dean's List

## **AWS Cloud Practitioner Certificate**

June 2023

## PROJECTS (github.com/Sukhpreet-s)

## Entertainment Dive (Web app/Plugin)

React, TMDB API, Svelte (Plugin), Firebase

- Web interface to browse and save movies in wishlist.
- Browser plugin to save the name and website link of a movie/tv while watching.